<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Harald&#39;s Datenecke</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Harald&#39;s Datenecke</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What Does Density Look Like in Madison?</title>
      <link>/2020/01/30/what-does-density-look-like-in-madison/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/30/what-does-density-look-like-in-madison/</guid>
      <description>This is a follow-up to my previous post on where Madison is most dense. But what do these dense areas look like? Inspired by the “Every Lot” bot, I’ll use the static Google Street View API via the googleway package to (hopefully) create some visual sense of density.
## Code from previous post to get 10 most dense block groups in Dane Countylibrary(sf)## Linking to GEOS 3.6.1, GDAL 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Is the High Density in Madison? </title>
      <link>/2020/01/29/where-is-the-high-density-in-madison/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/29/where-is-the-high-density-in-madison/</guid>
      <description>A recent New York Times article reviews a new exhibit at the Skyscraper Museum and claims that “Everything You Think You Know About Housing Is Probably Wrong.” Much of it centers around population or housing density, or the perception thereof.
However you calculate it, the word “density” sounds a lot like a synonym for overcrowding and congestion, for too-tall buildings and greedy real estate developers, unwanted neighbors and lost parking spaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bike counts, temperature, and precipitation in Madison (Wis.)</title>
      <link>/2020/01/26/bike-counts-temperature-and-precipitation-in-madison-wis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/26/bike-counts-temperature-and-precipitation-in-madison-wis/</guid>
      <description>My home town, Madison (Wis.), has automated bike counters on two of the city’s busiest bike paths, the Southwest Path and the Capital City Trail. The data is available with hourly counts on Madison’s Open Data portal, spanning several years. In this post series I will combine the bike count data with climate data to investigate the relationship between bike counts, temperature, and precipitation. How many more (or fewer) people bike on a day that is 5 degrees colder, or when it snows?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some further zoning analyses for Madison</title>
      <link>/2019/06/25/some-further-zoning-analyses-for-madison/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/25/some-further-zoning-analyses-for-madison/</guid>
      <description>I got some good feedback after posting my article on Madison’s zoning restrictions on Facebook and Reddit, prompting some additional analyses.
Why do you look only at residentially zoned land?Several people pointed out that comparing the zoning districts that only allow detached single-family homes (SFR) to all residential zoning districts may be misleading. In many cities the densest parts are not in residential zoning districts but in downtown areas zoned for mixed use.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>